HARRY LEGG

01720 423364 — ISLES OF SCILLY, UK — HARRY.LEGG86@GOOGLEMAIL.COM

in www.Linkedin.com/in/harry—legg—scilly/

HARRYLEGG.CO.UK/

PROBLEM SOLVER - PHILOMATH - PROFESSIONAL - PRAGMATIC - PURPOSEFUL - PLAYFUL - PUNNY - PROUD

PROGRAMMER

I will provide value to your business and enjoy learning so that I can provide even greater returns tomorrow. I have experience dealing with clients and other members of the public where my qualifications help me explain the software I have used and created. Understanding a system is the first step towards mimicking or improving it and there is nothing I love more than learning about how things work.

Education

Northumbria University 2004-2008 Computer Games Software Engineering BSc (Hons) 2:1

Truro College 2002-2004:

A Levels: Computing: B

Maths: C

VCE: Media: C
AS Levels: Product Design: C

Isles of Scilly Secondary School 1997-2002: 11 GCSEs A-C including separate sciences & geography

Other Qualifications

2013 - Preparing to Teach in the Lifelong Learning Sector (PTLLS) Level 4

Experience and Employment

- Lead Member for Environment, Climate Change and Waste at the Council of the Isles of Scilly: May 2022-Present
- Councillor at Council of the Isles of Scilly May 2017-Present
- 28 Miles™ Website full stack development and maintenance 2014-2019
- St Agnes Website Vacancies full stack development and maintenance 2010-2020
- Private Tutor Programming (HTML, Javascript) 2018-2020
- Lifelong Learning Tutor at Council of the Isles of Scilly 2013-2017
- IT Drop-in Support Assistant at Council of the Isles of Scilly 2014-2017
- Self Employed commercial egg production, packaging and distribution 2018-2022
- Self Employed commercial lobster fisherman 2008-2018
- HM Coastguard Rescue Officer 2009-2020
- South West Ambulance Service Co-Responder Volunteer 2002-2015
- Post Office Clerk at Starbeck Avenue Post Office 2007-2008
- Shop Assistant at St Agnes Post Office Stores 2002-2007

Skills

Problem Solving

Having been self employed, running my own businesses on a small, isolated island I have had to be resourceful and independent when it comes to solving problems. First I gain a good understanding of what caused the problem so that I can solve it in a way that will prevent it recurring or new issues from arising because of the solution. Large problems can seem daunting to tackle at first but I have yet to find an issue that cannot be broken down into smaller tasks which can be approached one at a time. Sometimes it is not the solution that is the challenge but identifying the fault, having a methodical approach is as important when fixing a broken diesel boat engine as it is when debugging code.

Programming

My degree focused on programming in C++ but by the final year we were computer linguists, having learned to understand a broad range of programming principles. Since university I have used many web technologies to produce dynamic websites and tools. (Javascript, HTML, CSS, PHP, MySQL, Node.js, React) In my spare time I have been using Unity and C# to create simple games for my children.

Strategic Decision Making

Sitting as an elected member on a Unitary Authority Council I take shared responsibility for setting a balanced revenue budget of over £6m, we also have a capital program of almost £14m with other projects that the Council are involved with up to £50m. We are responsible for delivering a broad range of services including adult's social care, children's social care, environmental health, licensing, planning, health overview and scrutiny, waste and recycling. I also sit on the Inshore Fisheries Conservation Association, Cornwall and Isles of Scilly Local Nature Partnership, Isles of Scilly Area of Outstanding Natural Beauty Partnership, South West Regional Flood and Coastal Committee and I chair the Climate Change Working Group.

Teaching

I have always helped people to understand complex concepts and learn in a way that works for them, focusing on retention of knowledge and skills built on a good foundation of the subject. Taking the PTLLS level 4 course really helped me to expand and demonstrate my teaching skills which I put into practice writing and teaching beginner and intermediate spreadsheet courses as well as an introduction to computing course for over 50s. I also enjoyed tutoring a high school student in HTML and Javascript focusing on basic programming techniques, he has gone on to get distinction stars at College and secured a place on a computer science degree at Nottingham University.

Communication

In my role as a councillor it is important to communicate well, in a professional manner with a wide range of people, such as members of the public, Council Officers, other elected members and colleagues from other organisations. I sit on the Communications Working Group where we discuss how Council Comms policy should be applied to current news items.

Customer Service

Having worked in retail I have experience dealing with a wide range of customers. I have also worked in a technical support capacity where I provided members of the public with IT support on their own devices at drop in sessions, I was also able to use my teaching skills at these sessions to explain how to use various software to achieve what the customer wanted.

Addional Information

Applications: Office 365 (Word, Excel, Power Point, Outlook), Firefox DevTools, Visual Studio Code, GIMP, Unity, Blender

Languages: C++, C#, HTML, CSS, Javascript (jQuery, Node.js, React), PHP, MySQL